<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Freedoom news feed</title>
  <link href="https://freedoom.github.io/" />
  <link href="https://freedoom.github.io/" rel="self" />
  <id>https://freedoom.github.io/atom.xml</id>
  <author><name>Freedoom Project</name></author>
  <updated>2019-10-10T01:22:22Z</updated>
  <entry>
	<title>Freedoom 0.12.0 released</title>
	<id>https://freedoom.github.io/#_2019_10_10_freedoom_0_12_0_released</id>
	<updated>2019-10-10T01:22:22Z</updated>
	<content type="html">
	  &lt;h2&gt;General&lt;/h2&gt;
	  &lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			We now have a manual rendered to beautiful PDF format.  Thanks to
			Simon Howard, the project’s founder.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			A strong focus on vanilla compatibility has been sought for this
			release.  Most, if not all, levels should work now.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			&lt;em&gt;Final Doom&lt;/em&gt; compatibility de-emphasized.  Where it creates
			conflicts with &lt;em&gt;Doom II&lt;/em&gt; mods or texture definitions, we prefer
			the &lt;em&gt;Doom II&lt;/em&gt; side of things.  &lt;em&gt;Final Doom&lt;/em&gt;-specific maps and mods
			may never look completely right in &lt;em&gt;Freedoom&lt;/em&gt;, as a result.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	  &lt;/ul&gt;
	  &lt;h2&gt;Levels&lt;/h2&gt;
	  &lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			&lt;em&gt;FreeDM&lt;/em&gt; has seen a major overhaul, with most maps being modified,
			with new additions and removals of the weaker levels.  It now
			benefits from the use of Aquatex and Egyptian textures in some of
			its levels, giving a more vibrant feel than before.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			&lt;em&gt;Phase 1&lt;/em&gt; gets a lot of mapping love in this round, fleshing out
			the levels and tweaking difficulty levels so easy, normal, and
			hard are all accounted for.  There is a new C3M5 by Mortrixs.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			&lt;em&gt;Phase 2&lt;/em&gt; MAP01 saw an overhaul, simplifying its design in
			significant ways to improve the flow around the level.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			Two maps in &lt;em&gt;Phase 2&lt;/em&gt; were replaced due to being recreations of
			&lt;em&gt;Doom II&lt;/em&gt; maps.  Jayexetee and GooseJelly get credits for the new
			ones, in MAP06 and MAP26.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			Maps in &lt;em&gt;Phase 2&lt;/em&gt; in general have had some slight re-arrangement
			based on difficulty levels and themes.  A new MAP06 by Jayexetee
			is included, the old one taking the MAP18 slot.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			All levels are now guaranteed to have co-op and deathmatch starts.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	  &lt;/ul&gt;
	  &lt;h2&gt;Graphics&lt;/h2&gt;
	  &lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			New power-up (stealth, overdrive, and ultra-overdrive) sprites.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			New necromancer (arch-vile) sprites by Urric.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			Some weapon and ammo sprites have been tweaked and improved.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			Completed and enhanced set of &lt;em&gt;Evilution&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Plutonia&lt;/em&gt; textures.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			New skull-switches by MissLav.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			New SKY4 based on an astronomy photograph.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			Tweaked player sprites and HUD face by Ferk.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	  &lt;/ul&gt;
	  &lt;h2&gt;Music&lt;/h2&gt;
	  &lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			New tracks in C1M2, C2M3, C2M8, MAP03, MAP12, MAP22, MAP25, MAP26,
			MAP27, DM03, DM06, DM09, DM17, DM24, DM31, and DM32.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			All files in-tree have been renamed from *.mus to *.mid.  The file
			format must always be MIDI.  This makes it easy on music composers
			to actually work with the files.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	  &lt;/ul&gt;
	  &lt;h2&gt;Unix script and metadata&lt;/h2&gt;
	  &lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			Metainfo (formerly appdata) and desktop files have been brought up
			to the latest standard specifications and recommendations, using
			reverse-DNS for the project identifier, and a self-evaluated
			content rating.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			The launch shell-script changed the &lt;code&gt;PORT&lt;/code&gt; environment variable to
			&lt;code&gt;DOOMPORT&lt;/code&gt; to avoid conflicts with the genericly-named &lt;code&gt;PORT&lt;/code&gt;.  It
			also builds a sensible default &lt;code&gt;DOOMWADPATH&lt;/code&gt; environment variable
			to assist ports that do not have a hard-coded fallback.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			The script no longer tries to look for &lt;code&gt;boom&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;zdoom&lt;/code&gt;, nor
			&lt;code&gt;prboom&lt;/code&gt; by default, as these are ports no longer maintained.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	  &lt;/ul&gt;
	  &lt;h2&gt;Build system&lt;/h2&gt;
	  &lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			Freedoom’s build system now has a hard dependency on Python 3, in
			anticipation of Python 2’s end-of-life.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			We have moved from ImageMagick to Pillow, a Python library for
			graphics manipulation.  It provides faster build times as well as
			API stability.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			GIF files have been replaced with PNG files.  True PNG file format
			transparency is used instead of a cyan background.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
		  &lt;p&gt;
			&lt;code&gt;ASCIIDOC&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ASCIIDOC_MAN&lt;/code&gt; variables have been added to the
			Makefile to control the AsciiDoc implementation used to generate
			HTML and man page files.
		  &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	  &lt;/ul&gt;
	</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Freedoom 0.11.3 released</title>
    <id>https://freedoom.github.io/#_2017_07_18_freedoom_0_11_3_released</id>
    <updated>2017-07-18T23:38:45Z</updated>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;This point release is only to allow building from source with
      &lt;a href="https://github.com/Doom-Utils/deutex"&gt;DeuTex&lt;/a&gt; 5.0, and thus is
      considered unnecessary for any purpose other than distribution
      packaging.  There are no level, sprite, sound, music, or other asset
      changes from 0.11.2.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Freedoom 0.11.2 released</title>
    <id>https://freedoom.github.io/#_2017_03_15_freedoom_0_11_2_released</id>
    <updated>2017-03-15T02:24:01Z</updated>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;Solving a few more issues found in the previous release, this point
      release is more dry than the last one, but we hope that it just
      refines the game to make it better than before.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    Missing multiplayer starts have been added to several levels.
	    No map should be lacking anymore.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    A few mapping errors were repaired by changing sector heights.
	    Speedrunners can better appreciate smooth flow through the levels.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    Easy and normal difficulty levels have been tweaked.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    Par times for &lt;em&gt;Phase 1&lt;/em&gt; have been added.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    Cleaned up title screen using the Freedoom font for &lt;em&gt;Phase 1&lt;/em&gt; and
	    &lt;em&gt;Phase 2&lt;/em&gt; on screen.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Freedoom 0.11.1 released</title>
    <id>https://freedoom.github.io/#_2017_02_22_freedoom_0_11_1_released</id>
    <updated>2017-02-22T02:45:13Z</updated>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;We&#8217;ve had quite a good reception for 0.11 and are thankful to everyone
      sending feedback, both praise and criticism, we use it all for
      improving Freedoom further!  This point release repairs a few
      deficiencies found in the 0.11 release, and adds new resources.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;div class="ulist"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    1% armor bonus pickups are recolored from red to green.  They were
	    too easily confused for health pickups.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    New &lt;em&gt;TNT: Evilution&lt;/em&gt;-compatible textures.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    New pain bringer and pain lord sprites, replacing old concept
	    art-derived ones.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    A few map errors are fixed, including misaligned textures,
	    leftover Boom specials, and it should no longer be possible to get
	    stuck between a rock and a tree in &lt;em&gt;Phase 1&lt;/em&gt; C1M1.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    Brand new &lt;em&gt;Phase 1&lt;/em&gt; C3M1, replacing an old &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt;-inspired
	    level.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    Widescreen statusbar for ZDoom was removed.  This created
	    incompatibility with some mods, and mod compatibility is prefered
	    over visual enhancements.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    Fixed intermission text after using the secret exit in &lt;em&gt;Phase 2&lt;/em&gt;
	    MAP31, where obituary texts were incorrectly displayed instead.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    More new music tracks, providing better vanilla compatibility.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Freedoom 0.11 released</title>
    <id>https://freedoom.github.io/#_2017_02_16_freedoom_0_11_released</id>
    <updated>2017-02-16T03:53:21Z</updated>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;Another year, and one of &lt;em&gt;Freedoom&lt;/em&gt;'s biggest updates has arrived!
      One of the major developments we&#8217;ve had is the elimination of Boom as
      the target engine for game support.  While we are aiming for an
      eventual compatibility with Vanilla &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Freedoom&lt;/em&gt; should
      presently run on any limit-removing engine, which is nearly all of
      them.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;div class="ulist"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    Lots of new music.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    New levels, including C1M1 kicking off &lt;em&gt;Phase 1&lt;/em&gt;.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    Aquatex: over 200 new textures for mappers to use.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    New intermission screens.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    Some new weapon sprites: new pistol, new pickups.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    New medkit and armor pickup sprites.
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;
	    New project logo. 😀
	  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Freedoom 0.10 released</title>
    <id>https://freedoom.github.io/#_2015_12_15_freedoom_0_10_released</id>
    <updated>2015-12-16T02:03:04Z</updated>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;Another large update to Freedoom, representing many changes to the
      game, giving a better feel for being an independent game and fleshing
      out neglected areas of the project.  We&amp;#8217;re not done yet, but close!&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
      Brand new status bar.
      &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
      New sprites for the serpent and orb monster.
      &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
      New HUD graphics for the single- and double-barrel shotguns,
      missile launcher, and SKAG.
      &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
      New pain sounds for many monsters and the player.
      &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
      New maps in &lt;em&gt;Phase 1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Phase 2&lt;/em&gt;.
      &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
